<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[collabrency]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[collabrency]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/collabrency/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 18:46:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/collabrency/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 18:46:16 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Adding new words to the English language]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Adding new words to the English language</h1>,<a href="https://twitter.com/JAGpictures/status/1039596439888912384" data-role="cta">Tweet your love for collabrency</a>,<article><img src="https://imgflo.herokuapp.com/graph/2b2431f8e7ba7b0/8a3762d242a01f98da5c04fbf046bbd6/noop?input=https%3A%2F%2Fmedia.licdn.com%2Fmpr%2Fmpr%2Fshrinknp_400_400%2Fgcrc%2Fdms%2Fimage%2FC4D12AQEDnkvwq-F2vg%2Farticle-cover_image-shrink_720_1280%2F0%3Fe%3D1542240000%26v%3Dbeta%26t%3DFZ-_SaINC4IinmOQ4JnfTt6_xXR0uKmo7cNgiKwFYRc"><h1>Collabrency &amp; adding new words to the English language</h1><p>Last year we decided to add a new word to our lexicon, &quot;collabrency&quot; - A cross between collaboration and transparency. The need for a word that best</p></article>,<p>Last year we decided to add a new word to our lexicon, “<strong>collabrency</strong>” - A cross between collaboration and transparency. The need for a word that best describes how we should act and think about work was unmistakable. However I am not alone, English speakers are adding new ones at the rate of around 1,000 a year.</p>,<p>People invent new words all the time, but which ones actually make it into the dictionary? When lexicographers decide what words to add to dictionaries, they try to imagine what words people actually want to look up. There are two important factors to keep in mind here:</p>,<p>1) Is the word in widespread usage?</p>,<p>2) Does the word have staying power?</p>,<p>Here are some more recent additions with their official definitions. I am hoping <strong>collabrency</strong> will join their rank soon..</p>,<p><strong>1. Bling (n):</strong> Expensive, ostentatious clothing and jewelry.</p>,<p><strong>2. Bromance (n):</strong> A close but non-sexual relationship between two men.</p>,<p><strong>3. Chillax (v):</strong> Calm down and relax.</p>,<p><strong>4. Crunk (adj):</strong> Very excited or full of energy.</p>,<p><strong>5. D'oh (ex):</strong> Exclamation used to comment on a foolish or stupid action, especially one’s own.</p>,<p><strong>6. Droolworthy (adj):</strong> Extremely attractive or desirable.</p>,<p><strong>7. Frankenfood (n):</strong> Genetically modified food.</p>,<p><strong>8. Grrrl (n):</strong> A young woman regarded as independent and strong or aggressive, especially in her attitude to men or in her sexuality (A blend of “Grrrr” and “Girl.”)</p>,<p><strong>9. Guyliner (n): </strong>Eyeliner that is worn by men.</p>,<p><strong>10. Hater (n):</strong> A person who greatly dislikes a specified person or thing.</p>,<p><strong>11. Illiterati (n):</strong> People who are not well educated or well informed about a particular subject or sphere of activity.</p>,<p><strong>12. Infomania (n):</strong> The compulsive desire to check or accumulate news and information, typically via mobile phone or computer.</p>,<p><strong>13. Jeggings (n):</strong> Tight-fitting stretch trousers for women, styled to resemble a pair of denim jeans.</p>,<p><strong>14. La-la Land (n):</strong> A fanciful state or dream world. Also, Los Angeles.</p>,<p><strong>15. Locavore (n):</strong> A person whose diet consists only or principally of locally grown or produced food.</p>,<p><strong>16. Mankini (n):</strong> A brief one-piece bathing garment for men, with a T-back.</p>,<p><strong>17. Mini-Me (n):</strong> A person closely resembling a smaller or younger version of another.</p>,<p><strong>18. Muffin Top (n):</strong> A roll of fat visible above the top of a pair of women’s tight-fitting low-waisted trousers.</p>,<p><strong>19. Muggle (n):</strong> A person who is not conversant with a particular activity or skill.</p>,<p><strong>20. Noob (n):</strong> A person who is inexperienced in a particular sphere or activity, especially computing or the use of the Internet.</p>,<p><strong>21. Obvs (adv):</strong> Obviously.</p>,<p><strong>22. OMG (ex):</strong> Used to express surprise, excitement, or disbelief. (Dates back to 1917.)</p>,<p><strong>23. Po-po (n):</strong> The police.</p>,<p><strong>24. Purple State (n):</strong> A US state where the Democratic and Republican parties have similar levels of support among voters.</p>,<p><strong>25. Screenager (n):</strong> A person in their teens or twenties who has an aptitude for computers and the Internet.</p>,<p><strong>26. Sexting (n):</strong> The sending of sexually explicit photographs or messages via mobile phone.</p>,<p><strong>27. Textspeak (n):</strong> Language regarded as characteristic of text messages, consisting of abbreviations, acronyms, initials, emoticons. (wut hpns win u write lyk dis.)</p>,<p><strong>28. Totes (adv):</strong> Totally.</p>,<p><strong>29. Truthiness (n):</strong> the quality of seeming or being felt to be true, even if not necessarily true.</p>,<p><strong>30. Twitterati (n):</strong> Keen or frequent users of the social networking site Twitter.</p>,<p><strong>31. Unfriend (v):</strong> Remove (someone) from a list of friends or contacts on a social networking site.</p>,<p><strong>32. Upcycle (v):</strong> Reuse (discarded objects or material) in such a way as to create a product of higher quality or value than the original.</p>,<p><strong>33. Whatevs (ex, adv):</strong> Whatever.</p>,<p><strong>34. Whovian (n):</strong> A fan of the British science-fiction television series Doctor Who.</p>,<p><strong>35. Woot (ex):</strong> (Especially in electronic communication) Used to express elation, enthusiasm, or triumph.</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ea1a4777-53a6-48a8-a599-42ee002ef235.jpg">,<h2>Luckily we have a good understanding of the how we words get created and eventually added to the dictionary, All new words are created by one of following mechanisms:</h2>,<p><a href="https://www.dictionary.com/e/getting-words-into-dictionaries/">https://www.dictionary.com/e/getting-words-into-dictionaries/</a> (This link has detailed information on how a word eventually gets added to the dictionary)</p>,<p><strong>1 Derivation </strong>The commonest method of creating a new word is to add a prefix or suffix to an existing one. Hence realization (1610s), democratise (1798), detonator (1822), preteen (1926), hyperlink (1987) and monogamish (2011).</p>,<p><strong>2 Back formation </strong>The inverse of the above: the creation of a new root word by the removal of a phantom affix. The noun <em>sleaze</em>, for example, was back-formed from “sleazy” in about 1967. A similar process brought about pea, liaise, enthuse, aggress and donate. Some linguists propose a separate category for lexicalization, the turning of an affix into a word (ism, ology, teen), but it’s really just a type of back formation.</p>,<p><strong>3 Compounding </strong>The juxtaposition of two existing words. Typically, compound words begin life as separate entities, then get hitched with a hyphen, and eventually become a single unit. It’s mostly nouns that are formed this way (fiddlestick, claptrap, carbon dating, bailout), but words from other classes can be smooshed together too: into (preposition), nobody (pronoun), daydream (verb), awe-inspiring, environmentally friendly (adjectives).</p>,<p><strong>4 Repurposing </strong>Taking a word from one context and applying it to another. Thus the crane, meaning lifting machine, got its name from the long-necked bird, and the computer mouse was named after the long-tailed animal.</p>,<p><strong>5 Conversion </strong>Taking a word from one word class and transplanting it to another. The word <em>giant</em> was for a long time just a noun, meaning a creature of enormous size, until the early 15th century, when people began using it as an adjective. Thanks to social media, a similar fate has recently befallen friend, which can now serve as a verb as well as a noun (“Why didn’t you friend me?”).</p>,<p><strong>6 Eponyms </strong>Words named after a person or place. You may recognize Alzheimer’s, atlas, cheddar, Alsatian, diesel, sandwich, mentor, Svengali, wellington and boycott as eponyms – but did you know that gun, dunce, bigot, bugger, cretin, currant, hooligan, marmalade, maudlin, maverick, panic, silhouette, syphilis, tawdry, doggerel, doily and sideburns are too? (The issue of whether, and for how long, to retain the capital letters on eponyms <a href="http://www.gsbe.co.uk/grammar-capitals.html">is a thorny one</a>.)</p>,<p><strong>7 Abbreviations </strong>An increasingly popular method. There are three main subtypes: clippings, acronyms and initialisms. Some words that you might not have known started out longer are pram (perambulator), taxi/cab (both from taximeter cabriolet), mob (mobile vulgus), goodbye (God be with you), berk (Berkshire Hunt), rifle (rifled pistol), canter (Canterbury gallop), curio (curiosity), van (caravan), sport (disport), wig (periwig), laser (light amplification by stimulated emission of radiation), scuba (self-contained underwater breathing apparatus), and trump (triumph. Although it’s worth noting that there’s another, unrelated sense of trump: to fabricate, as in “trumped-up charge”).</p>,<p><strong>8 Loanwords </strong>Foreign speakers often complain that their language is being overrun with borrowings from English. But the fact is, English itself is a voracious word thief; linguist David Crystal reckons it’s half-inched words from at least 350 languages. Most words are borrowed from French, Latin and Greek; some of the more exotic provenances are Flemish (hunk), Romany (cushty), Portuguese (fetish), Nahuatl (tomato – via Spanish), Tahitian (tattoo), Russian (mammoth), Mayan (shark), Gaelic (slogan), Japanese (tycoon), West Turkic (horde), Walloon (rabbit) and Polynesian (taboo). Calques (flea market, brainwashing, loan word) are translations of borrowings.</p>,<p><strong>9 Onomatopoeia </strong>The creation of a word by imitation of the sound it is supposed to make. Plop, ow, barf, cuckoo, bunch, bump and midge all originated this way.</p>,<p><strong>10 Reduplication </strong>The repetition, or near-repetition, of a word or sound. To this method we owe the likes of flip-flop, goody-goody, boo-boo, helter-skelter, picnic, claptrap, hanky-panky, hurly-burly, lovey-dovey, higgledy-piggledy, tom-tom, hip hop and cray-cray. (Willy-nilly, though, came to us via a contraction of “Will he, nill he”.)</p>,<p><strong>11 Nonce words </strong>Words pulled out of thin air, bearing little relation to any existing form. Confirmed examples are few and far between, but include quark (Murray Gell-Mann), bling (unknown) and fleek (Vine celebrity Kayla Newman).</p>,<p><strong>12 Error </strong>Misspellings, mishearing, mispronunciations and mis transcriptions rarely produce new words in their own right, but often lead to new forms in conjunction with other mechanisms. Scramble, for example, seems to have originated as a variant of scrabble; but over time, the two forms have taken on different meanings, so one word has now become two. Similarly, the words <em>shit</em> and <em>science</em>, thanks to a long sequence of shifts and errors, are both ultimately derived from the same root. And the now defunct word helpmeet, or helpmate, is the result of a Biblical boo-boo. In the King James version, the Latin <em>adjutorium simile sibi</em> was rendered as “an help meet for him” – that is, “a helper suitable for him”. Later editors, less familiar with the archaic sense of meet, took the phrase to be a word, and began hyphenating help-meet.</p>,<p><strong>13 Portmanteaus </strong>Compounding with a twist. Take one word, remove an arbitrary portion of it, then put in its place either a whole word, or a similarly clipped one. Thus were born sitcom, paratroops, internet, gazunder and sexting. (Note: some linguists call this process blending and reserve the term portmanteau for a particular subtype of blend. But since Lewis Carroll, who devised this sense of portmanteau, specifically defined it as having the broader meaning, I’m going to use the terms willy-nilly.)</p>,<p>Jagnoor</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/collabrency/adding-new-words-to-the-english-language/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">0583229f-7b80-466a-98b8-b6f38b5a0766</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 04:51:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>